X-Rated: The Greatest Adult Movies of All Time is a
documentary film directed by Eli Cross.
The evolution of adult cinema through the most influential films in
history, a journey that begins in the 1970s and ends nowadays.
An in-depth analysis of the success of the most prestigious erotic films, their impact on
industry and society, and their influence on cinema and contemporary culture.
Self - Host, played by Chanel Preston.
Self, played by Christy Canyon.
Self, played by Georgina Spelvin.
Self, played by Janine Lindemulder.
Self, played by Jenna Jameson.
Self, played by Jessica Drake.
Films generate income from several revenue streams, including theatrical
exhibition, home video, television broadcast rights, and merchandising.
However, theatrical box-office earnings are the primary metric for trade publications in assessing the success of a film, mostly because of the
availability of the data compared to sales figures for home video and broadcast rights, but also because of historical practice.
Included on the list are charts of the top box-office earners (ranked by both the nominal and real value of their revenue), a chart of high-grossing films by
calendar year, a timeline showing the transition of the highest-grossing film record, and a chart of the highest-grossing film franchises and series.
All charts are ranked by international theatrical box-office performance where possible,
excluding income derived from home video, broadcasting rights, and merchandise.
Traditionally, war films, musicals, and historical dramas have been the most popular genres,
but franchise films have been among the best performers of the 21st century.
There is strong interest in the superhero genre, with eleven films in the
Marvel Cinematic Universe featuring among the nominal top-earners.
The most successful superhero film, Avengers: Endgame, is also the second-highest-grossing film on the nominal earnings
chart, and there are four films in total based on the Avengers comic books charting in the top twenty.
Other Marvel Comics adaptations have also had success with the Spider-Man and X-Men properties,
while films based on Batman and Superman from DC Comics have generally performed well.
Beyond the superhero genre, Star Wars is the most represented
franchise in the nominal earnings chart with five films.
Although the nominal earnings chart is dominated by films adapted from pre-existing
properties and sequels, it is headed by Avatar, which is an original work.
Animated family films have performed consistently well, with Disney films
enjoying lucrative re-releases prior to the home-video era.
Disney also enjoyed later success with films such as Frozen and its sequel, Zootopia and its sequel, and The Lion King (along with its
computer-animated remake), as well as its Pixar division, of which Inside Out 2, Incredibles 2, and Toy Story 3 and 4 have been the best performers.
Beyond Disney and Pixar animation, China's Ne Zha 2 (the highest-grossing animated film),
and the Despicable Me and Shrek series have met with the most success.
While inflation has eroded the achievements of most films from the 1960s and 1970s,
there are franchises originating from that period that are still active.
Besides the Star Wars franchise, James Bond films are still being released
periodically; both are among the highest-grossing franchises.
Some of the older films that held the record of highest-grossing film still have respectable grosses by today's standards, but
no longer compete numerically against today's top-earners in an era of much higher individual ticket prices.
When those prices are adjusted for inflation, however, then Gone with the Wind—which was the
highest-grossing film outright for twenty-five years—is still the highest-grossing film of all time.
All grosses on the list are expressed in U.S.
dollars at their nominal value, except where stated otherwise.
The film explores themes of pornography,
interview, filmmaking, adult filmmaking.